Yingying,
婴婴
what happened to you?
你 你怎么这样了
Did they punish you?
你 你受罚了
Your Highness,
三公主
in order to protect you,
小人为保护您
I sneaked into the enemy and almost got killed.
混入敌军 九死一生
I could have been dead.
险些 就回不来了
Young Master, Chuchu,
少君 二姐
he has suffered a lot.
他都这副惨样了
I don't think he exposed the camp site
我估计他也不是
on purpose.
故意要暴露营地的
Let's spare him this time.
要不这回先饶了他吧
Perhaps we should send him back.
不如将他送回去
That's right.
是啊
So, you're not gonna stick to
少城主这会儿
the seven times of capture and release thing?
不想要七拿七放了
Hey...
这
Where did you get the jade pendant?
你怎么会有这个玉佩
Jade pendant?
玉佩
It's a family heirloom.
那是小人家传的配饰
It's one of a kind.
世间仅此一块
It was broken
这两日
into two pieces.
不知为何少了半边
I must have chipped it
许是做事的时候
by accident.
不小心碰碎了吧
I found the other half of the jade pendant
我在困住我的陷阱里
in the trap.
找到了这枚玉佩的另外半边
Did you break it
该不会是你安排陷阱的时候
while you were setting the trap?
不小心弄碎了吧
It was my fault.
都是小人的错
I arranged all of this.
是小人安排的
It has nothing to do with Her Highness.
与三公主无关
Yingying!
婴婴
What arrangement did you make?
安排何事
Get me trapped, of course.
自然是安排我掉进陷阱
I just don't understand
只是不知道少城主这样指使他
why you asked him to do this.
有何居心
No, no, Chuchu.
不是的 不是的 二姐
It was a mistake. I just...
你误会了 我只是
You just want me to get trapped
只是将我掉进陷阱
so that Meng Guo could capture me.
引孟过来抓我
However,
却没想到自己的人
your people lit the fire
燃起了炊烟
which attracted Meng Guo here.
引来了孟过
No, no, no. I...
不不不 我
Your Highness,
二郡主
you're accusing Her Highness unjustly.
您怎么能如此冤枉三公主呢
She found out that you had a crush on Young Master Han,
她只是见您属意韩少君
so she asked me to trap you
便吩咐小人将您困在陷阱里
so that Young Master Han could come to your rescue.
再引韩少君去搭救
She was trying to fix you up with Young Master Han.
想撮合您二人啊
Anyway, she was doing this for your good.
说到底 也是为了您好
She was definitely not setting you up.
绝对没有陷害您的意思
Why are you explaining everything?
你说得可真够清楚的
Didn't you say it has nothing to do with me?
你不是说跟我没关系吗
But I can't just let you be wronged.
小人也不能看二郡主误解您啊
So, you mean,
你这话的意思就是
what he said is true?
他说的都是真的
Chen Qianqian,
陈芊芊
I used to think of you as a willful girl.
我以前只觉得你任性
But now,
现在看来
I find out that you don't have a heart.
你还没有心
Chuchu, please forgive me. I...
二姐 你别怪我 我
I don't blame you.
我不怪你
In fact, I should be thanking you.
我还得谢谢你呢
If you really want me to have him,
三妹若真有心将韩少君让给我
you should do more of this stuff.
不如多做些这样的事情
If you do this a few times,
你多让他几次
he'll get over you.
他便再也不会想着你了
I'm gonna peel it off.
揭了啊
Young Master Han,
韩少君
I brought this medicine from Huayuan City.
这是我从花垣城带来的伤药
Let me get you patched up.
我替少君包扎一下吧
Qianqian is naughty.
芊芊胡闹惯了
Please don't take it personally.
少君别往心里去
Women enjoy a high status
我们花垣城
in Huayuan City.
向来以女子为尊
In her eyes,
在芊芊眼里
you're no different than a new toy,
少君和一件新鲜玩物没有不同
something she'd toss aside when she has lost interest.
不想要了 就送给别人
You need to get over this.
少君还是想开一些好
Your Highness is so considerate,
还是二郡主细心
unlike your younger sister.
哪像少城主
Bai Ji,
白芨
what are you doing here?
少城主来这儿干吗
You got injured because of me.
少君是因为我受伤的
I'm here to give you some medicine.
我特意给你带了药过来
Thanks.
少城主客气了
How come you know that I like...
你怎么知道我喜欢吃这
Your injury...
你的伤
Why Han Shuo is wearing
楚楚的东西
Chuchu's sachet?
怎么会在韩烁身上
Please take care of yourself.
那你好好养身体啊
Now I'll take my leave.
我先回去了
Apologies for my abruptness.
刚才唐突了
I should go now.
那我先回了
Thank you, Your Highness.
多谢二郡主
He said he was irritated.
嘴上说着生气
But his body was telling a different story.
身体倒是很诚实嘛
They got so close when she put medicine on him.
上个药靠这么近
How could he say that I don't have a heart?
说我没有心
Come on, I was trying to fix him up with Chuchu
我这一整颗心
with my whole heart!
都帮他拿来追楚楚了 好吗
The screenwriter should be blamed.
编剧就是背黑锅的
How could she blame me for the character she created?
自己写的角色还要埋怨我
When did Su Ziying
那个苏子婴
get injured?
什么时候受的伤
I think he was faking it.
属下觉得他只是在伪装
Why did Young Master Chen keep defending him?
少城主怎么还护着他
Keep an eye on him.
盯住了
I want to know
我倒要看看
why Pei Heng
裴恒放这么一个人在芊芊身边
sent him to Qianqian.
是何居心
Understood.
是
It's difficult terrain in Weimeng Mountain.
威猛山地势复杂
Meng Guo has occupied the place for a long time.
孟过长期占据此处
He knows well the local terrain and climate.
对此处的地势和天气十分了解
He is likely to...
很有可能把
Perhaps I should leave them alone.
还是让他们两个人单独相处吧
Let's go.
走
...put it here.
安排在这儿
Young Master Chen,
少城主
Stop!
你给我站住
Come down here.
下来
Come back.
回来
Stand right there.
站好了
Well, you guys go on the discussion. I'll go upstairs.
要不 你们先计策着 我上楼
Suppressing the bandits seems really easy for you.
少城主剿匪可真省事
You have left the job
不仅将抓捕一事
to Her Highness and Young Master Han.
推给二郡主和韩少君
Now, you don't even care enough to give orders.
如今连嘴皮都懒得动了
Zi Zhu, what are you talking about?
梓竹 你什么意思
I didn't say that I'll stay out of this.
我也没说我不帮忙啊 是不是
The stockade is located in the woods, in the downwind direction.
山寨地处林间 位于下风向
We could use...
可用
Fire attack!
用火攻
Fire attack.
火攻
It's a low-lying area. The back hill...
而且地势低洼 后山
Here!
这儿
Water attack.
水攻
It's easy for you to say.
少城主说得倒是轻松
You only need to say the words.
一抓一放还不是您沾沾嘴皮的事
But Her Highness and Young Master Han have to do the work.
倒是辛苦了我们二郡主和韩少君
They've been exhausted these days.
这些日子 腿都要跑断了
Zi Zhu, mind your words.
梓竹 放肆
When I keep silent,
这 我不说话吧
you'd say I'm not helping.
说我不帮忙
When I say something,
我一说话吧
you'd say I'm just saying.
说我只动嘴皮子
You're very resourceful.
少城主多足智多谋啊
No wonder you can come up with the trap thing.
怪不得能想出挖陷阱的方式
Don't you think so?
是吧
Not really.
我还不够足智多谋
If I'm that resourceful,
我要够足智多谋
you wouldn't have found out what I did.
就不会被你们发现了
It seems you
我看近日少城主
has been worried
为了我和二郡主
about me and Her Highness.
是劳心劳神吧
It's necessary to have some brain-boosting dishes.
得吃点好的补补脑子
Bai Ji?
白芨
I'm here.
在
Tell her
给咱们的少城主
what we're gonna have today.
报报今天的菜谱
Steamed pigeon.
清蒸鸽
Braised pigeon.
红焖鸽
Fried pigeon.
油爆鸽
Roasted pigeon.
叫花鸽
Stewed pigeon.
炖老鸽
All about pigeons?
都是鸽呀
Where did you get so many pigeons?
怎么那么多鸽
Perhaps Pei Heng
这许是裴恒
wants to keep you full.
怕你饿着了
Bai Ji, let's go.
白芨 走吧
Keep me full?
怕我饿着
Sir.
公子
Any news from Weimeng Mountain?
威猛山那边还没有消息吗
None of the homing pigeons
您送出去的信鸽
have come back.
一只都没有回来
How come?
怎么会这样呢
I heard that Young Master Chen
听闻少城主
had arrested Meng Guo the bandit.
已擒获山匪孟过
Young Master Chen is courageous and resourceful.
少城主智勇双全
It's a good thing
于城主 于花垣城
for Your Majesty and the city.
都是一大喜事
Congratulations.
真是可喜可贺
Finally, she has done a good job.
芊芊总算是争气些了
May Young Master Chen return in triumph!
遥祝少城主凯旋
Report!
禀告城主
We got news from Weimeng Mountain.
威猛山传来消息
When will she come back?
少城主何日回城
She is not coming back for some time.
少城主暂时无法回城
Perhaps she is having fun out there.
这孩子就是贪玩
Alright, just let her.
罢了 先让她游玩几日
Get Meng Guo here first.
先把孟过押送回来
Your Majesty, please calm down.
城主息怒
Young Master Chen has released Meng Guo again.
少城主又把孟过给放了
What?
什么
Again?
又放了
How many times did she
这抓了放 放了抓
release him after the arrest?
这都第几回了
Please calm down.
城主息怒
Perhaps Young Master Chen is doing this for fun.
少城主兴许就是图个消遣
I beg to differ.
刘司银此言差矣
Young Master Chen is a smart girl.
少城主聪慧伶俐
I don't think she'd miss the big picture.
不是不顾全大局之人
She must have done this
这样做
for a purpose.
想必有她的用意
This is ridiculous.
真的是太胡闹了
I would love to know
我倒要看看
what she is trying to do.
她到底想干什么
Please go on with the banquet.
大家请继续
Sangqi,
桑奇
has Your Majesty got any other news
近日 城主可曾得到
about Qianqian?
芊芊那边的其他消息
You, come over here.
你 过来
You're Su Mu, the most popular musician of the Music and Dance Academy, aren't you?
这不是教坊司花魁苏沐吗
Since when do you start paying visit to the Mansion?
什么时候也来这城主府邸走动了
Like I said,
我就说嘛
I wouldn't
也就只有少城主
put it past Young Master Chen.
能干得出这种事
Please let us know
什么时候重回教坊司
when you decide to return to the Music and Dance Academy.
记得知会我们一声
Come on.
来
Drink it.
喝酒
Su Mu, come over here.
苏沐 你过来
This is a thank-you gift
这是你日日前来照看我
for your taking care of me these days.
替芊芊帮我复健的谢礼
Your Highness, I'm afraid it's inappropriate.
大郡主 这可万万使不得
I'm just a musician.
苏某只是一介乐人
How could a humble person like me...
身份卑微 怎
You're a guest of honor in this house.
你是日晟府的上宾
No one is to look down on you.
谁敢轻看你
Since when has Su Mu been in the good graces of Her Highness?
这苏沐何时得了大郡主的青眼
Now everyone has to treat him with dignity.
往后 可没人敢轻薄他了
That's right.
可不就是吗
How do you know that I was pretending to surrender?
你怎么知道我是诈降
It's not the seventh time yet.
这还没到七次呢
There is no way you would seriously surrender.
你怎么会真心降服呢
You're so smart.
少城主真乃神人也
This time,
此次
are you gonna release me as before?
是不是也要把我放了呀
Yes!
放
The whole thing is easy for you because you didn't do the work yourself.
每次不是你去抓人 你不累
How many times have we done this?
这都放几次了
Do you really plan to repeat the whole thing seven times?
真打算七擒七放吗
The wise man?
什么诸葛孔明
Military counselor?
什么军师
Does he even know anything about the art of war?
他懂兵法吗
Chuchu,
二姐
Meng Guo is a brave and simple guy.
这孟过他骁勇善战 心思单纯
Once he is totally convinced,
他要是被真心降服了
he'd be a gallant soldier for us.
定是一位猛将
Chuchu,
二姐
we only need to do this one more time.
就差最后一次了
This is the one last time,
这差最后一次了
we shouldn't give up.
咱不能放弃
That's right, give me one more chance.
对呀 再给我次机会嘛
Give him a chance.
给他一次机会
Your Highness,
郡主
Young Master Chen is in charge of this.
毕竟此次剿匪的首领是少城主
We'd better let her make the decision
决定由她来做
in case you get in trouble.
也免得您受连累
By now,
算着时间
the Mansion must have got the news.
消息应该已经传回城主府了
Release him.
敬听少城主吩咐
Cut me loose.
解开
Do it quickly.
快点松
Tomorrow in the noon,
明日午时 营外十里
I'll meet you at the place 5 km from the camp.
愿与少城主一战
Have a safe trip home!
慢走啊 路上小心
See you!
去吧
Tomorrow,
这明日
we're gonna have the final battle.
就是我们的最后一战
We'll be divided into two groups.
咱兵分两路
I'll be luring
一路 由我自己个儿
the enemy in
诱敌深入
while Young Master Han and Chuchu
一队 由韩少君跟二郡主
will capture Meng Guo
从后面包抄
by outflanking him from the back.
一举拿下孟过
I have no objection.
我没有异议
Young Master Han, what's your take on this?
不知少君意下如何
Do you really want me to be on the same team with Her Highness?
你当真 要我与二郡主一路
Fine.
也好
However, if the plan doesn't work out
不过 若计划出现疏漏
and we couldn't come to your rescue
少城主真的对上孟过
while you're confronting Meng Guo,
我与二郡主都来不及驰援
what then?
又该如何
Meng Guo once claimed
孟过曾口出妄言
that he'd capture you alive and possess you.
说要生擒少城主 霸占陈芊芊
Can you guess what he is trying to do?
你猜 他有什么企图
You're young and beautiful.
咱们少城主正值青春年少
If you end up in his hands...
若不幸落到孟过的手上
Oh my God!
天啊
I need to think of some way to protect myself.
那我是得想一个庇护自己的办法
So, what's your plan
不知少城主
for tomorrow?
明日究竟该做何安排
It seems
那我明日
I mustn't go solo tomorrow.
定不能自己行动了
Then who do you want to work with?
那少城主想跟谁一块行动呢
Chuchu?
二 二姐
I'd rather not.
别了
I'm afraid you'll release him again
我怕与你一路
after we arrest him.
抓到孟过 又要放他
How about...
你不如就
I won't release him.
不会的 二姐
Not this time.
这回真的不会了
I won't let him go.
不会放过他的
Qianqian, you can...
芊芊 不然你就
Chuchu?
二姐
Your Highness,
三公主
if Mr. Pei is here,
若此时我家公子随行
he'll protect you with his life.
定会护三公主周全
He cares about you so much
公子对三公主情深意重
that he sent me to take care of you all the time.
才派小人随行照料
However, to his disappointment,
只是 小人不堪大用
I wasn't competent enough
只能眼看着三公主只身赴险
and failed to protect you.
辜负了公子嘱托
That's right.
对呀
Perhaps you should join Pei Heng.
不如你和裴恒一路吧
What are you talking about?
你说什么风凉话呢
Pei Heng is like a thousand miles away.
裴恒远在千里
You could bring his portrait along with you
那少城主可以带上他的画像
and burn some incense.
然后再烧上三炷高香
That should work.
你看他顶不顶用
Bring his portrait?
我带他的画像
I might as well bring yours
不如带你的画像
since you look far more intimidating than him.
你长得比他凶狠多了
Your portrait must work better.
带你的定能辟邪
So, you will bring my portrait?
少城主愿意带着我的画像
Then why wouldn't you work with me?
那 那你为何又不愿与我同行
When did I say that?
我什么时候说不愿意跟你一路了
You've been bossy to me.
你每天对我横挑鼻子竖挑眼的
Why would I get myself into such trouble?
我干吗自己找不痛快
Please calm down, Your Highness.
三公主息怒
You could stay at the camp
不如您留守营地
while Young Master Han and Her Highness go separate ways.
让韩少君和二郡主分头行动
You'll just have to wait here.
您静候佳音
That way, I'll still be all by myself at the camp.
留守营地不还是一个人吗
Do you really consider staying at the camp?
你还真想守营地呀
Well...
那
Anyway,
总归就是
you just don't want to be by my side, do you?
你不想与我在一处 是吧
I... I...
我 我
Mr. Han, don't worry,
小人定不辜负公子嘱托
I'll protect Her Highness with my life.
拼死保护三公主
Bai Ji,
白芨
let's go.
我们走
Chuchu?
二姐
Tomorrow, Young Master Chen will be guarding the camp.
明日少城主镇守后方
In case anything happens,
如果遇到危险
let off fireworks to send the distress signal.
记得以烟花为信
Understood.
是
Zi Rui, let off the fireworks!
梓锐 快放烟花求救
Here you are.
来了来了
We're so dead.
完了
Your Highness,
三公主
I don't think anyone will come to the rescue now.
这下 没人能救你了
Our luck has run out.
玩脱了
Report!
报
Mr. Han,
启禀少君
the scout said
探子来报
Meng Guo and his guys have passed Her Highness's ambush
孟过已带人越过二郡主伏击
and made his way to our camp.
直奔我军营地而去
Oh my God!
糟了
Meng Guo took Young Master Chen away.
少城主被孟过抓走了
Meng Guo once claimed
孟过曾口出妄言
that he'd capture you alive and possess you.
说要生擒少城主 霸占陈芊芊
Can you guess what he is trying to do?
你猜 他有什么企图
You're young and beautiful.
咱们少城主正值青春年少
If you end up in his hands...
如果被孟过给抓去了
(Owner of Xuanhu City) What is it? The vision board?
这什么 愿望清单啊
Does a bandit
都是山匪了
have KPI?
还有关键绩效指标吗
Occupy Huayuan City and destroy Xuan...
占花垣 灭玄
In your dream!
你做梦去吧你
That's never going to happen.
你这辈子都不可能
Get the Dragon Bone.
夺龙骨
That's my fault.
是我的问题啊
I'll fix it.
让你断了这念想
Capture Young Master Chen...
生擒少城
Well, you actually did it.
这你倒是做到了
Mr. Meng, you want to have the ceremony now?
大哥 现在就拜吗
Yes.
拜
No time like the present.
趁着今天赶紧拜了
The sooner, the better.
以免夜长梦多
Understood.
是
The ceremony?
拜 拜堂
What ceremony? Is he forcing me to marry him?
这拜什么 不是抢亲吗
What are you doing?
你干什么
Listen,
我告诉你
I've released you so many times.
我 我放了你那么多回
Shouldn't you release me this time?
你是不是也得象征性地放我一次
It's called reciprocity.
礼尚往来你懂不懂
If you won't let me go,
如果你不愿意放我
just sit down with me.
咱俩就坐着谈一谈
Listen,
我告诉你
don't hurt me,
你 你别动我啊
or Han Shuo will come after you.
韩烁不会放过你的
He will definitely come to my rescue.
他肯定会来救我的
If you hurt me,
你 你要是敢动我
he will show you no mercy.
他饶不了你
When he is irritated,
他这个人虎起来
you have no idea what he is capable of.
比老虎还虎
I'm not looking.
我不看
Meng Guo!
孟过
I am the Crown Princess of Huayuan City.
我 堂堂花垣城少城主
There is no way
我是不会向你们这些
I'll surrender to a gang of bandits.
地痞流氓屈服的
Take one more step,
你再过来
I'll kill myself
你要是敢逼我
right in front of you!
我就以死明志了啊
Young Master, this is all mistaken.
大当家的 误会我了
What is the situation now?
怎 怎么了
Young Master,
大当家的
your mom sent you here to suppress the bandits.
你奉你娘亲的命令 前来剿匪
But you released me every time you arrested me.
却对我六抓六放
Do you know why?
为 为啥
Why?
为 为什么
Because you think highly of me and want to test me.
那是因为你看重我 要考验我
You can tell all that.
这 这都被你看出来了
You see good qualities
少城主
in me.
看出了我孟某人的实力
Yes.
是
You're the person who discovers me.
是我孟某人的伯乐
This is your grace to me.
这就是对我有恩
You keep your word by arresting and releasing me for six times.
六抓六放 绝不食言
This is your loyalty to me.
这是对我有义
You've treated me with nothing but grace and loyalty.
少城主对我有天大的恩义
I must
我必须
pay you back.
要报 报答你
Pay me back?
报 报答我
By kidnapping me over here to have the wedding ceremony?
你 你把我掳到这山上跟我拜堂
Wedding ceremony?
拜 拜堂
No.
不
The ceremony is about us becoming sworn brothers.
我是要跟你拜 拜把子
Being the ruler of Weimeng Mountain
来我威猛山做山大王
is way more comfortable
不比当那花
than being the Crown Princess of Huayuan City.
花 花垣城少城主快活
For the seventh time,
这第七次
I arrested you.
虽是我抓了你
But I'd like to surrender myself.
但我孟过 降了
Zhuge Liang
这孔明
really is a wise man.
真乃神人啊
Mr. Meng,
孟大哥
from now on,
从此以后我们可就是
we're brother and sister unrelated by blood.
异父异母的亲兄妹了
As far as I'm concerned,
按我的意思
you're welcome to be the ruler
你就来我这威猛山
of Weimeng Mountain.
做我的山大王
Please don't say no.
你 不要推托
OK.
我不推托
I'll be the ruler here.
我来做大当家
Guys, greet her!
兄弟们 叫人
Young Master!
大当家
Mr. Meng!
二当家的
Hey, you always
对了 孟大哥
look down on women from Huayuan City.
你一向是瞧不上花垣城的女人
Why would you follow me now?
为何现在又肯归顺于我
Though you're a woman,
你虽是女人
you're so bold and resourceful
但是 你有勇有谋
that even ten men are no match for you.
十个男人也比不上
Even I am no match for you.
我也比不上
I'm totally okay with you being the leader.
你当老大 我没话说
You're the bigger person. I admire you for that.
佩服啊 孟大哥 这胸襟
What smells so good?
什么味 这么香
We're having a feast
为了欢迎你入寨
in your honor.
弟兄们准备了酒席
Guys, let's get it started!
兄弟们 开坛喝酒
Okay.
好
Young Master,
少君
the stockade has been besieged.
我们已经将山寨团团围住
We can attack at any time.
随时可以进攻
Young Master Han,
韩少君
I just caught a bandit.
我刚拿住一个山匪
We can get some information from him.
打探一下消息
Why are you people bustling in and out?
山上怎么这么热闹
Mr. Meng ordered us to prepare a feast.
我们大当家下令准备酒席
We're having a ceremony today.
毕竟大喜的日子
What ceremony?
什么大喜的日子
What else could it be?
还能有什么大喜
The wedding ceremony
肯定是那孟过
for Meng Guo and Young Master Chen, of course.
要强娶我们少城主啊
Bai Ji, give the order. Attack.
白芨 下令 攻寨
Understood.
是
Cheers.
干了
Young Master Chen, your story of seven times of capture and release
大当家七擒七放的故事
has become a legend
真是千古流传
to be remembered.
名垂青史啊
I'm so impressed.
小弟佩服 佩服
With you guiding us,
有了大当家率领我们
no one would dare suppress us.
看谁以后敢剿匪
We'd conquer
来一个 打一个
every enemy we have.
来一群 打一群
Let's drink the wine.
喝喝喝
Cheers.
喝 干
Let's keep a low profile.
咱这得 低调
There is not much that I can promise,
这其他的我不敢保证
but as long as you follow me,
只要兄弟们好好地跟着我
the entire Huayuan City
我敢说 这整个花垣城
will be ours.
都是咱们的囊中之物
Great! Great!
好 好 好
However,
但是呢
I want to make three statements.
我要立三个规矩
First,
这第一
we don't rob people's houses.
就是咱不能打家劫舍
Young Master,
大当家
never have we robbed someone poor.
咱们兄弟从来不劫贫苦的百姓
We only rob caravans that pass by.
只劫过路的商队
Second,
这第二呢
we don't kidnap women.
就是不能强抢民女
Women are the ones who kidnap us.
我们都是被民女强抢
We only became bandits in the mountains
宁死不从
because we wouldn't accept that fate.
才被逼上了山 当山匪的
Exactly.
就是
Alright, alright.
行行行
Third,
这第三
have that character corrected.
就是能不能把那字给我改一下
Did you see anything wrong?
看出问题没
There you go.
这样子才对嘛
Pour the wine.
倒酒
Mr. Meng,
二当家的
it seems Young Master Chen
这大当家的
miswrote the character.
是不写错字了
I have heard it long before
早就听闻这传闻中的三公主
that Her Highness is illiterate.
是个大字不识的人
It turns out to be true.
还真是如此
However, now that she is our leader,
但既然她当了咱们大当家
let's do as she says.
她说什么就是什么
From now on, this is the one.
以后这字就念寨
Understood.
是
Report!
报
What's up?
怎么了
Mr. Meng,
二当家的
a troop of soldiers has arrived at the foot of the mountain.
山下来了队护城军
They're about to attack.
快打上来了
It must be Han Shuo.
一定是韩烁
There are so many of us.
我们这么多人
Besides, we have Young Master Chen.
况且还有大当家的在
We don't need to be afraid of them.
还怕他们不成
Han Shuo is Young Master Chen's husband,
韩烁毕竟是大当家的男人
making it inappropriate to have a fight with them.
总不能打起来吧
Well...
这
Who dares to attack Weimeng Mountain?
竟然有人敢攻打我们威猛山哪
Guys, let's go!
小的们 冲
Who is attacking us?
谁要打我威猛山啊
Step aside. Step aside.
让让 让让 让让
Who is the person in charge?
把管事的给我叫出来
This way.
这边
Young Master, are you alright?
少城主 你没事吧
Young Master?
少城主
Why do you call me that?
什么少城主
Now, I'm the ruler of Weimeng Mountain.
我现在是威猛山的大当家的
I'm no longer the Crown Princess.
不当少城主
Where is Chuchu? She should be the Crown Princess.
楚楚呢 楚楚当
Young Master, please don't say that.
少城主 这话可不能乱说
Get over there.
你过去吧你
I,
我
I am the ruler of Weimeng Mountain.
我是威猛山的老大
I am afraid of nobody.
我谁也不怕啊
Chen Qianqian,
陈芊芊
do you even remember why you were sent here?
你还记得你是来剿匪的吗
Who is this? He look quite handsome.
谁呀 这小模样长得还挺标致
What about coming with me and becoming my husband?
你要不跟我回去当压寨夫君吧
He is your husband.
这是你夫君
Since when have I married such a handsome man?
我什么时候有这么好看的夫君了
When and how did we get married?
什么时候来的 怎么来的
You kidnapped him.
抢回来的 抢回来的
I'll do it again.
那我就再抢一次
Let me check it.
验验货啊
How many packs do you have?
你这 几块腹肌呀
How many packs?
腹肌啊 这得呀
Young Master, let's talk about it later.
少城主 咱回去说吧
He is shy.
害羞
Let's talk about it later.
有什么事咱回去说啊
Turn around, all of you.
都给我转过去
You guys just look away.
你们也别看了啊
Stop it.
别闹了
Come back with me.
跟我回去
You know what?
我跟你说
You look exactly like someone I know.
你长得特别像一个人
He told me
可是那个人以前说
that he'd protect me all the time.
他说 一直保护我的
However, at a critical moment,
但是到关键的时候吧
he got mad at me
他跟我怄气
and scared me with the bandit thing.
还拿山匪吓唬我
In the end, he left me alone at the camp.
最后他把我一个人留在营地里
It was my fault.
是我不好
I'm here for you.
我这不来了吗
Han Shuo?
韩烁
What took you so long?
你怎么才来呀
I was freaked out. I was...
我都快怕死了 我都快
Look at their swords.
你就看他们那大刀
Those huge swords.
多大的刀啊
It's okay. It's okay.
好了 好了 好了
It was all my fault.
是我不对
You can punish me all you want.
你打我骂我怎么样都行 好吗
You belong to the heroine.
你是属于女主角的
Put her down!
放下我们大当家的
Stop!
站住
Young Master,
少君
what about these people?
那这些人怎么办
Now that you follow the leadership
既然你们认定
of Qianqian,
芊芊是你们大当家
you should come back to the camp with her.
那就跟她一起回营
From now on,
此后威猛山众人
you take orders from Young Master Chen.
归顺少城主 为她所用
You should behave yourselves
回到花垣城后
in Huayuan City.
不准目无法纪
Those who disobey the rule will be punished.
违命者 军法处置
Let's go.
走啊
Come on, let's follow Young Master Chen.
走吧 跟大当家走
Since when have I married such a handsome man?
我什么时候有这么好看的夫君了
When and how did we get married?
什么时候来的 怎么来的
You kidnapped him.
抢回来的 抢回来的
Chen Qianqian,
你说你
you didn't make any progress
别的本事没长
except on drinking.
净长酒量上了
How dare you tempt him?
谁都敢撩
That will teach you to go easy on wine.
看你下次还敢不敢喝酒
Young Master Chen.
少城主
Here is the refreshing soup for you.
来 喝点醒酒汤
Su Ziying brought it by this morning,
这是苏子婴一大早送过来的
saying it's for you.
说让你喝下
Your Highness!
三公主
Zi Rui, from now on,
梓锐 从现在开始
keep a closer eye on Su Ziying.
你给我死死盯住苏子婴
Prevent him from causing me any trouble.
别让他再给我搞事情了
Understood.
是
Take it away.
收走
Come in.
进
Your Highness, you've been exhausted these days.
二郡主 您近日太过操劳
I prepared this nourishing soup for you.
小人熬了补汤
Hope you enjoy it.
二郡主请用
Leave it there. You're excused.
放那儿 退下吧
Your Highness,
二郡主
you'll recognize me
等我替您夺回少城主之位
once you are reinstated to the Crown Princess with my help.
您就会想起我是谁了
Did you find out anything?
事情查清楚了吗
What did you find out?
怎么说
Did you see your young master?
你家少君呢
Your Highness, you're awake.
少城主 你醒了
I have good news for you.
告诉你一个好消息
We have suppressed the bandits with our army intact.
此次剿匪没费一兵一卒
All of them have surrendered to us.
全员归顺
Young Master is planning on the return.
少君正在部署班师回城的事情
We're leaving tomorrow.
明日就出发
Alright, alright.
行行行
Young Master, Her Highness is looking for you.
少君 少城主找您呢
Who told you to say...
谁让你跟我说
Are you still mad at me?
还在生我的气呀
Are you planning to never talk to me again?
你真打算一辈子不跟我说话
I was wrong.
我错了
I shouldn't get mad at you.
我不该和你怄气
I shouldn't scare you with the bandit thing.
也不该拿孟过吓唬你
I shouldn't freak you out
更不该把你一个人扔在营地
by leaving you alone at the camp.
害你受了惊吓
Yesterday, I was also frightened.
昨天我也特别怕
I was thrilled
后来见你没事
to see that you were fine.
我不知有多高兴
Actually, it's not completely your fault.
其实也不能全怪你
It was I who screwed it up.
是我 是我搞砸了
Why were you
那你之前为何
mad at me?
一直要生我气
setting me up with Her Highness?
凑在一起啊
That's because you two are supposed to...
那是因为你们俩本来
Yes, I tried to approach your sister.
我先前虽然有意要接近你二姐
But I didn't know you back then.
那时候不是还不认识你吗
You once said
你说过
that you need to learn what a person likes before you give him a gift.
送人东西前 先问喜不喜欢
It seems
怎么到你这里
you didn't stick to it
处理起事来
when it comes to setting me up with someone.
就全然不顾我喜不喜欢
Since you have kidnapped me,
既然三公主抢了我
you should see it through.
就要对我负责到底
Your Highness,
二郡主
I'll see that you win over
只要是您喜欢的人
the person you like.
我一定帮您得到他
Today, we're not serving pigeons.
今日就别给芊芊吃鸽子了
Go hunting in the woods.
你去林间打点野味
Prepare some food for Qianqian.
给她压压惊
Understood.
是
Sir.
公子
Young Master Han,
禀告韩少君
I'm here to deliver a message from Young Master Chen.
少城主命小人来传信
She wants to meet you at the storage room of the inn
说约韩少君今日申时
this afternoon.
在客栈杂货间见面
She has something to tell you.
说 有要事相谈
The storage room?
杂货间
Yes.
是的
Later, I want you to hide yourself.
一会儿 你先藏起来
Once Young Master Han walks into the storage room with the other person,
等韩少君和另一位进了杂货间
you lock the door immediately.
就立刻锁上门
Understood.
小的明白
Wait till the drug to take effect.
记得算好药效发作的时间
You can rest assured of that.
您放心吧
Young Master.
少城主
Young Master, you're right about Su Ziying.
少城主 如您所料
He is up to something.
这个苏子婴 果然不老实
He wants to lure Young Master Han to the storage room.
他居然想把韩少君骗到杂货间
He even plans to drug him.
还要给韩少君下药呢
What drug?
下 下什么药啊
I don't know.
我不知道啊
Where is Han Shuo?
韩烁人呢
By now...
按照时间来算的话
Get to the point!
快点
He is on the way to the storage room.
在去往杂货间的路上了
Su Ziying
这个苏子婴
has the blackest heart in the world.
就是包了黑芝麻馅的汤圆 黑心
He even pulled one over on me.
连我都骗过去
Young Master, where are you going?
少城主 您干吗去呀
To save him.
我救人去
I want you to get Su Ziying
我告诉你啊
under control.
把苏子婴给我稳住了
How am I supposed to do that?
我应该怎么稳住他呀
Qian...
芊
Han Shuo?
韩烁
Han Shuo, are you alright?
韩烁 你怎么了
Get up. Let's go.
你起来 来 走
I'll get you out of here.
我带你出去 走
Let's go.
走
What are you doing?
你干什么
What's wrong with you?
你干什么 韩烁
Get out of here.
快走
I'm poisoned with aphrodisiac incense.
我中了合欢香
Aphrodisiac incense?
合欢香
Young Master Chen?
少城主
Zi Rui?
梓锐
Zi Rui, open the door for me! Hurry up!
梓锐 帮我把门打开 快点
Okay.
好
Help me!
救我
Young Master Chen, the door is locked.
少城主 这门锁上了
I can't open it.
我打不开呀
I'll get some help.
我去找人帮忙
Hold on, hold on.
等等 等等 等等
Listen,
我跟你说
don't make it public.
此事不宜声张
If you have no one to turn to,
你谁都信不过
just find Bai Ji.
你去找白芨 白芨
Understood.
好
Young Master Chen, hang in there.
少城主 你挺住啊
Wait for me.
你等我呀
I can hang in there.
我倒是挺得住
But I don't think Han Shuo can.
我就怕韩烁他挺不住
Mr. Su!
苏公子
Mr. Su, you're finally here.
苏公子 你可算来了
Han Shuo is already in there.
韩烁已经在里头
Young Master Chen is in there, too.
少城主也在里头了
What? How come Young Master Chen is in there?
这 怎么会是少城主
It's Young Master Han and the Second Princess
我明明要锁的
that I want to lock in there.
是韩少君与二郡主
What's the problem with you?
你乱锁什么
Didn't you say
不是你跟我说
Young Master Chen wanted to meet him here?
少城主约他在这儿见面吗
It was a lie.
我那是佯称
How can you take it seriously?
你怎么给当真了
Oh my God!
完了
Young Master Han and Young Master Chen
韩少君跟少城主
are locked in the room.
都锁里头了
Where is the key?
钥匙呢
I can't find it.
钥匙 不见了
Just look for it.
回去赶紧找啊
I put it right there.
刚才我就藏在这儿的
Han Shuo,
韩烁
stop right now or I'll hit you.
你要再这样 我就不客气了
Will it
用这个砸他
kill him?
会不会把他砸死
Who knocked me out?
刚才 是谁打晕的我
Did Chen Qianqian suspect me?
难道 陈芊芊怀疑我了
Put on the clothes.
衣服披上
It's cold here.
杂货间冷
Bai Ji will come for me
白芨等会儿发现我不见了
when he finds out that I'm missing.
自然会寻过来的
Han Shuo, listen to me,
韩烁 我跟你讲
this is the time for the hero
一般这种时候就是
to show his decency.
看男主人品的时候
You must survive the ordeal.
你一定要经得住考验啊
Your Highness! Your Highness!
三公主 三公主
Are you in there?
您在里面吗
Su Ziying?
苏子婴
I couldn't find you anywhere.
小人到处找您找不着
It turns out you're locked in.
原来您被锁在里面了
Get me out of here.
你 你快救我出去
I'll think of some way to help you.
小人这就想办法救您出去
When I get out of here,
等我出去
I'll leave you to Han Shuo for disposal.
我把你交给韩烁处置
All screenwriters write about aphrodisiac incense that way.
这个药别人都这么写
I just jumped on the bandwagon.
我也就这么写了
However, in the original script,
可我原本写的是
Su Ziying used this drug
苏子婴用这个药
to fling Han Shuo and Chuchu together.
来撮合韩烁跟楚楚的
I never expected
没想到啊没想到
this would happen to me.
居然应验到我自己身上了